这里是  Polycasters 开发者
ROB DODSON: Hey there, Polycasters.
我是 Rob
Rob here.
几集以前  我就开始去了解
A few episodes ago, I started this little journey
去试着弄明白 Polymer 的数据绑定系统
to try and understand Polymer's data binding system.
从那时候开始  我就观察它的性能影响情况
And since then we've looked at property effects, path
信息通知功能  并且观察使用 observer 时在 JavaScript里
notifications, and watching for changes in your JavaScript
发生的变化
using observers.
因此  今天让我们一起来近距离看看
So today, we're going to bring it all to a close
数组绑定究竟是什么情况
by finally looking at array bindings.
让我们现在就开始看看
Without further ado, let's hop in.
好的  假设你获取到一个数组形式的列表
All right, so let's say you've got a list of users in an array.
或许会是广告栏形式  或许是一个排行榜形式
Maybe it's like a leaderboard or a high scores list
或者像这样的
or something like that.
你也学会想把这个用户显示在第一个位置上
And you always want to show the user that is in the first position.
一般来说  你也许会这么做
Now logically, you might do something
你会采用数组的方式去绑定用户  如 users
like this, where you try to use array syntax to bind to users
加方括号 0
square brackets 0.
然而  这样的语法实际上对于 Polymer 的
However, syntax like that is not actually supported
数据绑定不被支持
in a Polymer binding.
相反 Polymer 处理这些数据项  却很像
Instead, Polymer treats items in an array much the same way
对象调用方法的形式
as it treats subproperties in an object.
就是加上路径
It turns them into paths.
因此你获得信息时  从 users 加方括号 再加0
So you've got users square bracket 0,
变成了 users 加点再加 0 的方式
and Polymer's actually going to change that to users.0.
最后来添个插曲  我给你展示下
Now in the last episode, I showed you
你使用 observer 会发现一些变化
how you can watch for changes on a path using observers.
你可以在这个地方检查下
You can check that out over there.
因此让我们用新的方法来绑定用户数据
So let's change our binding to use this new approach.
我将创建一个属性变量  取名为 firstUser
I'm going to create a property called firstUser.
然后  我会创建一个观察者
And then, I'm going to creater an observer which
用来观察用户的数组内容  数组在这里
is watching the user's array-- this array right here.
我们用一个星号来观察数组内容
It's watching that user's array using an asterisk.
请记住  这个星号或者万能表达式
And remember, that asterisk or that wild card
能查看到数组的任何内容改变情况
will watch for any changes in the array
或者它对象的方法和其他内容
or its subproperties, et cetera.
它将调用这个操作函数  当第一个参数变量的
And it will call this handler function with a change record
内容顺序发生变化
as the sort of first argument.
然后我再传第二个参数
And then I can actually pass the second argument.
我可以传 0
I can pass 0.
这个将作为第二个参数传给
And that will then serve as the second argument
这个函数  这里将被视为 index
to the function, which we'll use as our index.
因此这个数组如果发生变化
So anytime this array changes, we're
我们将通过这个操作符获得变化的记录
going to get a change record in this handler.
如果你想起来前几集的视频
And if you recall from the previous episode,
可以想到  改变记录我们可以使用记录的多种属性
change records have multiple properties that we can use.
其中一个就是 base 属性
One of those properties is the base property,
这就是以前经常用星号引用的对象
which always refers to the object previous to the asterisk.
因此在这个例子里  它也就经常回调访问用户的数组
So in this case, it's always going to refer back to our user's array.
因此我们可以发现  实际上我们想要的是 base 对象
So we can say that we want the base object, and we
并且获取到 index 对应的条目
want the item at that index.
因此这可以说  返回的是 users 的 0 位置数据
So this is basically saying, hey, return users 0.
所以  这里请看右边  可以通过实际的操作来观察下
So over here on the right, we can actually see this in practice.
我将使用精巧的 Chrome DevTools 工具
I'm going to use my little tricky Chrome DevTools
方法来选择我们的条目
method to select my item.
我将用 Polymer 的 unshift 方法
I'll use Polymer's unshift method
向用户数组里再传一些新的值
to pass a new value into its user's array.
然后我们就可以看到上面内容发生了改变
And then we can see that that is reflecting up there,
因为一旦我们设置了新的内容属性
because once we've set this new property,
它将马上更新我们这里绑定的数据内容
it's updating our binding right there.
并且这两边是匹配的
And those two match up.
酷
Cool.
现在  我们能否简化下这个程序呢
Now, I was wondering if I could simplify this a bit,
并且  我注意到文档里  它实际
and I noticed in the documentation it actually
采用的是记录绑定方式
recommends using a computed binding.
因此让我改下代码  用另外一个种方式
So let's change the code to use that approach instead.
因此  现在我已经获得了  而不是已经创建了一个属性
So now I've got-- instead of a property that I've created,
我仅用一个计算绑定函数  这里我称作 computeUser
I'm just using a computed binding function I'm calling computeUser.
我任然使用这个万能表达式方法来观察数组
I'm still using the wild card approach to observe that array.
当你观察 computeUser 的时候  它任然可以获得改变的记录
And when you look at computeUser, it still gets a change record.
它任然获得 index 变量  并且它仅仅
It still gets that index argument, and it just-- instead
设置一个属性  仅返回
of setting a property, it just returns the value back
它绑定的值
into this binding.
让我们稍作调整
So let's give that a shot.
好的
All right.
在这里  我将使用 unshift 函数向先前的数组里增加一个 user 变量
Go over here, I'll unshift a new user into the front of the array.
起作用了
And everything works.
现在对我来说  这个排序给了我些启示
Now for me, this was kind of a revelation of sorts.
我意识到计算绑定和观察者方式
I realized that computed bindings and observers
基本是相同的方式运行的
basically work the exact same way.
因此  如果你已经懂了一点的话
And so if you understand one, then you
随后你就会懂的其他的方法  这真的很棒
understand the magic of the other, which is pretty cool.
现在你也许会怀疑  如果我们仅
Now you might be wondering, if we're just
使用 path  我们就不能
working with paths, how come I can't just
绑定子属性啦  如果你想这么操作  就用 users.0 吗
bind to the subproperty, if you will, this users.0 path?
并且因为我们使用的是 Polymer 的数组方法
And then since we're using Polymer's array methods, which
它将负责通知  绑定的子项目属性
normally will notify items-- subproperty
发生了改变  如果我们使用的是这些数组方法
bindings of changes, if we're using those array methods,
如果我们不希望这些更新发生改变  这又该怎么办
then how come these things aren't updating as I would expect them to?
好的  这将发生什么
Well, what's actually going on is
是由这个初始值决定的
this will work for the initial render.
第一次我们是这么设定的  我将会发现数组里面第一个位置的
So the first time I do this, I will see the first place user
内容
from my array.
我们看见的是 Eric
I'll see Eric over there.
但是让我们看看如果我们输入进第二个 user 将会发生什么
But let's look at what happens when I try and push in a second user.
使用 unshift  这次我们将增加一个 Boris 姓名
So I'll unshift, and this time I'll ad a user named Boris.
很显然没发生变化  尽管
Nothing updates visually, although we
我们可以看到用户数组发生了改变
can verify that the users array has changed.
因此 Boris 现在应该就在第一个位置了
So Boris is now in that first position.
发生这种情况的原因是  在这种机制下
And the reason this is happening is because, under the hood,
Polymer 获取的是初始的 users.0 的数据
Polymer takes that initial path of users.0,
这种方式也有其自身的特点  不变的关键字
and it turns it into its own special, immutable key which
可以使你能一直跟踪某些数据项
you can use to keep track of the item.
这种方式  可以常用来回调先前的项
This way, it can always refer back to that item,
即使数组的顺序已经发生了改变
even if the order in the array has changed.
因此这就意味着  你不能真正可靠的
And so that means that you can't really reliably use
使用这些方法
this approach right here.
最好的举措就是
The best practice way of doing things
同时采用观察者方式和计算绑定方式
is to either use an observer or use a computed binding.
到现在  你已经是应该 Polymer 数据绑定牛人了
So with that, you are now Polymer data binding masters.
下周  我们将发布一个小的推文
Now last week, we sent out this little tweet
来收集大家的看法  看你们下集想听 Polycast 的那一部分的内容
asking what you wanted to see in the next episode of Polycast.
你们所有人都可以投票  并且也可以看到单元测试
You all voted and said you wanted to see unit testing.
因此确保你一直关注我们  下周我们将
So be sure to stick around when next week we
发布网络测试题
cover web component tester.
同时  如果您喜欢我们这集视频的话  请点击下面
In the meantime, though, be sure to click that little Subscribe
的订阅按钮
button if you've enjoyed this episode.
如果你有任何疑问
If you have questions for us, you
你可以联系我们  用你的社交网络发布 同时加上 #AskPolymer
can ping us on a social network of your choosing at #AskPolymer.
总之  感谢您的收看
As always, thank you so much for watching.
我们下次再见
I'll see you next time.
播放音乐
[MUSIC PLAYING]